[Music]
it's time to put paint in the master
bedroom I'm hoping that the Wagner smart
sidekick powered paint roller is going
to make that job a whole lot
easier okay so I have gotten as far as I
can in this room doing prep work before
any kind of major repair work happens it
would seem that on one of the walls I
will probably have to replace a very
large section of sheetrock so I'm not
ready for that just to keep the project
going I want to try and get some paint
up on this wall that's what I've been
trying to do and one thing is I
absolutely hate to paint I hate it I
hate doing it I don't know why I know
some people love it
but when it comes to projects painting a
room is the bane of my existence so I'm
kind of always looking for a way to make
it easier now this isn't product
placement this isn't anything sponsored
I bought this product because I am
always looking for something like I said
to make my painting easier so what I
bought for about $80 was the Wagner
smart sidekick now what this is is
essentially a pressurized paint roller
and it looks like there's an electric
pump that lives inside of this housing
that connects to the side of the paint
gallon and you can use it in a 5 gallon
bucket as well it does have an extension
tube for that and what it's going to do
is in this suction tube it's going to
suck up the paint put it all the way
through the hose to the powered roller
now this is a perforated roller so on
the inside of it it does have
perforations the paint will go all the
way through this tube into the roller
and be able to apply onto the wall it's
not the best solution obviously the
quickest and easiest thing would be a
sprayer but I don't want to use a
sprayer inside of an enclosed area plus
I just didn't want to spend the money on
it so I'm going to go ahead and give
this oral see how it works and give you
my honest reviews and feedback on it see
if it was worth the 80
bucks using the unit is relatively
straightforward once you have the pink
can handle in the straight up and down
position and you align it between these
two spots on the spout clamp now the
spout clamp adjusts upwards you slide
your gallon paint can in and then lower
the spout handles back down this also
gives you somewhere to place the suction
tube so it nicely and neatly sits inside
of the gallon of paint after that it's
relatively straightforward you plug in
the unit don't forget to turn it on and
then you press the power button and Away
you
go
let's hope that this is as intuitive as
I think it is and I should just have to
press the
button well might help if I turned it on
I
[Music]
guess all right it's starting to se
through the roller
nail see it coming
through all right and you do have
control over that so essentially what
you're doing is filling this roller with
paint and I'm going to just kind of keep
spinning it around until I see a good
saturation coming
[Music]
through so I think I'm going to start
spreading
this yeah there
[Music]
go
well so far I've gotten
already I don't know probably 2/3 of
this wall covered now the paint that I'm
using is the be Marquee one coat
coverage uh one thing I am noticing is
this handle is pretty cumbersome it's
very heavy obviously it's going to be uh
it does have an attachment at the bottom
for pull which I may go and get my pull
just so that I can use two hands with it
a little more easily um so far so good
the paint
roller is leaving a bit of a stippling
but behind it's not very smooth and you
do have to get specialized paint rollers
that are perforated that allow the paint
to come through and the rollers that you
have to use are not the greatest right
now but I'm going to let that sit in I'm
going to keep working on it and
hopefully this will make life a lot
[Music]
[Applause]
easier
[Music]
[Applause]
once I did have the paint pole
attachment on the paint roller it did
make the job that much easier it is
markedly more convenient to have the
paint on hand at the roller at all
[Music]
times you will notice that I do have to
keep finding bare spots on the wall to
spread the paint that is the one
drawback to this system is that you
don't know how how much paint is on the
roller so you do have to be careful of
how much is loaded up so you don't smear
on the wall as opposed to Rolling the
paint
[Music]
on all right so I've painted about the
equivalent of two standard size walls in
our master bedroom and I wanted to give
my opinion of the Wagner smart sidekick
paint roller system the big question can
spending $80 on a paint roller make me
like painting no uh I I hate painting
it's just I it's the pane of my
existence I do not enjoy doing it it's
always a task and a chore for me but I
bought this with the intention of making
painting easier so different question
will spending $80 on a paint rolling
system make painting a room easier yes
are there better ways to do it probably
if I bought a paint sprayer but I don't
need to paint these rooms in 10 minutes
I'm not spending hundreds of dollars on
a painting system that I'm not going to
use for a business purpose uh the things
that I like about this system you have
paint on hand you don't have to go
chasing down your bucket it's right
there you get paint just by pressing a
button it's super simple it's very
intuitive to use so those are big pluses
for it plus the price point $80 it was
inexpensive and I didn't really have any
qual spending that money getting
something that's going to make painting
a room easier the drawbacks that I've
seen the handle's made out of plastic I
worry that's not going to last very long
it did feel and sound like the handle
was creaking the paint roller creaks as
you use it but then again so has every
paint roller ever that I've ever used so
I don't think that's a problem specific
to this paint
system there's another big drawback in
having the paint on hand in the
perforated roller you don't know or at
least I don't know how much paint is on
that roller I did notice at times I did
start to run out of paint oh okay press
the button but for how long I don't know
I don't know how much pain is in that
roller until I go and try and spread it
so I tried different ways of hold it for
like 5 Seconds hold it for 10 seconds
hold it for 2 seconds 3 seconds and then
just keep seeing until I ended up more
often than not having way too much paint
in the roller and that is a bit of a
drawback cuz then I had to chase down a
bare wall to try and get some of the
paint spread out because I had too much
that's a major drawback for me but I
think that this system um you're going
to have that there's really no way to be
able to know how much paint's in there
are they going to have a level gauge to
tell you no of course not so bigger
question would I buy it again absolutely
I think so I would buy something like
this again this has made making painting
the room easier and that's what I was
after that was the biggest thing that I
wanted to have out of this is the hose
cumbersome yes dude I get tripped up on
it a lot yeah would I appreciate if
there was some kind of clip to keep the
hose on the pole mhm sure but I think
they have a little velcro attachment
that's probably what that's there for
and I didn't remember about so honestly
I would say that this was a good
purchase and it was something that is at
least going to make painting the rooms
easier for me thanks for sticking around
to the end of the video make sure to
like the video and subscribe leave us a
comment let us know if you've used a
paint system like this before or this
system how you felt about it is it worth
buying what's your opinion on it make
sure to keep an eye out for more videos
from the new Yankee homework selection
and also hopefully we'll have new videos
coming out on our new Yankee projects
and new Yankee auto systems for now
though we'll see you on the next
one
[Music]
a